Guide to the Stanford University, School of Education, Dean's Office, Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, School of Education, Dean's Office, records
1947-1960
SC0788
Stanford University. Graduate School of Education. Dean's Office.
1 Linear feet
Collection includes correspondence, reports, and other records regarding the American Ideals Project, which produced the book YOUR RUGGED CONSTITUTION, 1947-52; a file on the Lee L. Jacks and David Jacks Professorships, 1954; agenda, minutes, and other records of the Committee on University Policy and other university committees, 1959-60; two volumes of the unpublished versions of "Resource Units of the Committee on Democratic Citizenship" (National Council for the Social Sciences and the National Association of Secondary-School Principals); and the Proceedings of the Bay Area Conference on Human Relations Education, Stanford University, Jan.19, 1957. Deans represented include I. James Quillen and A. John Bartky.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Description of the Collection
Collection includes correspondence, reports, and other records regarding the American Ideals Project, which produced the book YOUR RUGGED CONSTITUTION, 1947-52; a file on the Lee L. Jacks and David Jacks Professorships, 1954; agenda, minutes, and other records of the Committee on University Policy and other university committees, 1959-60; two volumes of the unpublished versions of "Resource Units of the Committee on Democratic Citizenship" (National Council for the Social Sciences and the National Association of Secondary-School Principals); and the Proceedings of the Bay Area Conference on Human Relations Education, Stanford University, Jan.19, 1957. Deans represented include I. James Quillen and A. John Bartky.
Access Terms
Bartky, A. John, 1899-; Committee on Education for Democratic Citizenship.; National Council for the Social Sciences.; Quillen, Isaac James, 1909-; Stanford University. Graduate School of Education. American Ideals Project.; Stanford University. Graduate School of Education. Dean's Office.; Social sciences--Study and teaching.
Collection Contents
- Records, Accession ARCH-2005-361
  - American Ideals Project 1947-52 (1 of 4) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - American Ideals Project 1947-52 (2 of 4) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - American Ideals Project 1947-52 (3 of 4) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - American Ideals Project 1947-52 (4 of 4) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Lee L. Jacks and David Jacks Professorships, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Committee on University Policy, 1959-60 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Academic Council Executive Committee and other committees (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Budgetary background materials (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Assorted memoranda, 1959-60 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Quillen, I. James, "Achievement Standards in the High School," 1955 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Resource Units of the Committee on Democratic Citizenship (National Council for the Social Sciences and the National Association of Secondary-School Principals), Vol. 1. Contains the following:
    - 1. Using a Resource Unit (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - 2. American Defense (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - 3. Consumer Problems and Social Studies (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - 4. Democracy and Dictatorships (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - 5. Family Relations (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - 6. Government Finance (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - 7. Machines and Technology (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - 8. Politics in Action (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Resource Units of the Committee on Democratic Citizenship (National Council for the Social Sciences and the National Association of Secondary-School Principals), Vol. 1. Contains the following:
    - 9. The Problem of Crime (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - 10. Problems of Public Administration (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - 11. Public Opinion (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - 12. Race and Cultural Relations (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - 13. Recreation (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - 14. Technology and Society (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - 15. Youth (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Proceedings of the Bay Area Conference on Human Relations Education, Stanford University, Jan.19, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous items pertaining to education, not generated by S.U.S.E. (Box 2, Folder 4)